{
  "inkulsionInterview": [
    {
      "index": 0,
      "inklusionFrage": "What does the concept of inclusion mean to you?",
      "inklusionTagesmutter": "Anne Lindemann",
      "inklusionAntwort": "That's an intriguing question, one that I would have answered differently a few weeks ago. I happened to come across an interview where an autistic mother of five children shared her wishes about how people should interact with her. This interview left a profound impact on me, leading me to the following response.Inclusion is about coexisting within a community where every individual, regardless of their life circumstances, is accepted and respected for who they are as a person. It's not the society's task to force individuals into its systems but rather to learn how to foster a sense of togetherness, where each person's uniqueness is acknowledged and respected.Our responsibility is to learn from each other what needs exist. Every person should be able to experience in their life that 'as I am, I am accepted and valued."
    },
    {
      "index": 1,
      "inklusionFrage": "What experiences in disability support do you bring with you?",
      "inklusionTagesmutter": "Birte Lutterbei",
      "inklusionAntwort": "I've always been certain about my passion for working with people. Following my high school graduation, I chose to participate in a voluntary social service year at a center for individuals with disabilities. Subsequently, I completed training to become a state-recognized caregiver specializing in disabilities. I've dedicated around 12 years of my career as an educational specialist in disability care. My primary focus involved supporting and promoting the well-being of individuals with physical, mental, and intellectual disabilities."
    },
    {
      "index": 2,
      "inklusionFrage": "Considering your experience, how does the group dynamics change when caring for a person with disabilities within the daycare group?",
      "inklusionTagesmutter": "Anne Lindemann",
      "inklusionAntwort": "In my professional experience, I've noticed that within the elderly care setting, the initial interactions among residents are often quite natural and unguarded. The approach of the caregivers significantly influences how the group interacts. By embracing each resident for who they are, the others tend to follow suit, sometimes even more compassionately. I can recall a situation where one of the residents had a challenging skin condition that required careful attention. While it wasn't categorized as a disability, it demanded special care. This resident, despite facing discomfort at times, was inherently cheerful, sociable, and very open. Others in the community noticed the skin condition and often inquired with genuine concern. I took the opportunity to explain the situation and, in coordination with the resident's preferences, provided necessary care and attention. This routine became a ritual of sorts, and after certain activities, fellow residents willingly assisted in preparing for the required care, creating a sense of shared involvement and community bonding."
    },
    {
      "index": 3,
      "inklusionFrage": "What inspired you to concentrate on working with the elderly population, particularly those facing challenges or at risk?",
      "inklusionTagesmutter": "Birte Lutterbei",
      "inklusionAntwort": "Raising my own Grand Parents has significantly strengthened my desire to work closely with the elderly community. Since January 2021, I have been actively involved in elderly care. Leveraging my extensive experience, my primary focus is on inclusive care practices. I aim to offer families with elderly members facing challenges the option to receive professional care in a homely environment. Similar to any other family, they should have the choice between traditional care facilities and personalized elderly care. Within this setting, individuals have the freedom to develop at their own pace in a secure and serene atmosphere. Here, seniors can learn from one another early on, realizing that factors like appearance, background, language, or disabilities hold no significance."
    },
    {
      "index": 4,
      "inklusionFrage": "What fears and concerns might families bring to you in the context of elderly care?",
      "inklusionTagesmutter": "Anne Lindemann",
      "inklusionAntwort": "That varies significantly and is as individual as the elderly individuals placed under my care. However, every family desires their loved ones to be accepted within the community and to engage in social interactions. I must mention that, rarely, I had prior knowledge of a diagnosis before commencing care. In such instances, discussions took place where I asked questions, collaborating with the families to understand what I should be attentive to and aware of. Having a comprehensive understanding of child development in the first three years is highly beneficial. Even when dealing with challenges, I always recognized areas where the elderly individuals were particularly unique. With my certification in Inclusion Specialist, I'll be equipped with extensive knowledge to competently support families. However, it's equally important for me to assess my own limitations. I may not be the perfect fit for every family, and that's perfectly acceptable."
    },
    {
      "index": 5,
      "inklusionFrage": "What 'special services' do you offer to elderly individuals facing challenges or disabilities?",
      "inklusionTagesmutter": "Birte Lutterbei",
      "inklusionAntwort": "I consider it particularly important to individually nurture and guide each elderly person according to their strengths, interests, and preferences. I see myself as a 'development facilitator,' aiding the elderly in exploring and discovering the world around them. For me, this involves maintaining an open attitude toward differences, acquiring further knowledge and skills related to various conditions or challenges, and continuously adapting the environment. Creating spaces for relaxation is essential, allowing the elderly to find moments of peace. I am especially delighted about implementing a 'Snoezelen corner,' made possible through the Inclusion Voucher Program. This concept, initially designed in the Netherlands for individuals with disabilities, serves as a relaxation technique, enabling stress reduction and relaxation for the elderly. Through elements like fiber optic strands, mirrors, and a glowing water column, this environment invites individuals to dream. The 'Snoezelen' concept bridges connections among elderly individuals, whether they have specific needs or not. Additionally, the enriching experiences of interacting with animals at home offer holistic benefits to all. It could involve exploring nature together with the dogs, petting the donkeys, or feeding dandelions to the rabbits, creating opportunities for comprehensive experiences for everyone."
    },
    {
      "index": 6,
      "inklusionFrage": "What 'special offerings' do you provide to elderly individuals facing challenges or disabilities?",
      "inklusionTagesmutter": "Anne Lindemann",
      "inklusionAntwort": "I follow the principles of educator Emmi Pikler in my approach, incorporating elements such as the Pikler triangle, arches, and platforms. These encourage the residents' self-activity and facilitate autonomous movement development. I structure daily routines to provide residents with a sense of security and stability. I allocate time and space for free engagement, allowing residents to independently immerse themselves in their interests while providing support whenever requested. It's essential to me that each resident, especially during the initial years, can develop their individuality and self-awareness. Therefore, I offer special activities tailored to accommodate all residents' needs."
    },
    {
      "index": 7,
      "inklusionFrage": "Is there a network or any aspirations for the future in your perspective?",
      "inklusionTagesmutter": "Birte Lutterbei",
      "inklusionAntwort": "I greatly value the warm reception and meaningful interactions with my fellow caregivers in the local community. Currently, we have established an association (www.kitala-Ladbergen.de). Concerning our commitment to inclusive practices within elderly care, I seek greater transparency and support. Our current partners include healthcare professionals, social service agencies, and specialized advisory services. I aim to establish connections with various elderly care facilities in the area, striving together to ensure tailored and optimal care for each resident. When caring for individuals with specific needs, the number of simultaneous care responsibilities is adjusted accordingly, impacting service contracts. Looking ahead, my aspiration is to secure funded reserved slots for those requiring specialized care. This provision is essential to ensure availability as needed. A substitute care model should consider the unique needs of individuals requiring specialized attention."
    },
    {
      "index": 8,
      "inklusionFrage": "Have you already established a network?",
      "inklusionTagesmutter": "Anne Lindemann",
      "inklusionAntwort": "Among most elderly care facilities in Ladbergen, I frequently establish connections and aim to foster future collaborations. I am fortunate to have another caregiver specializing in elderly care, Birte Lutterbei, working in close proximity. Additionally, in the neighboring town of Lengerich, I am in contact with another professional in elderly care, also specializing in inclusive practices."
    },
    {
      "index": 9,
      "inklusionFrage": "What are your aspirations for the elderly individuals concerning their future?",
      "inklusionTagesmutter": "Anne Lindemann",
      "inklusionAntwort": "Yes, that's quite easily answered. Each elderly person, to me, deserves to be recognized as an individual with unique characteristics and distinct needs. It's our responsibility, acknowledging this individuality, to shape a community and society where everyone finds a place and acknowledgment. This doesn't occur in documents and reports but in direct interactions and mutual engagement."
    }
  ]
}
